

//   preguntas segun su dificultad
  // Preguntas f√°ciles
const easyQuestions = 
[
  // no importa el orden de las respuestas, el mismo codigo las revulve a la hora de mostrar
  // agarralo buenoo asi para mas rapido
  {
    question: "She will be studying for her exams tomorrow",
    answers: ["Future continuous", "Simple present", "Past continuous", "Simple future"],
    correctAnswer: "Future continuous"
  },

  {
    question: "They eat lunch at 12 p.m. every day",
    answers: ["Simple present", "Simple past", "Present continuous", "Simple future"],
    correctAnswer: "Simple present"
  },

  {
    question: "We were watching a movie when the power went out",
    answers: ["Future continuous", "Simple present", "Past continuous", "Simple future"],
    correctAnswer: "Past continuous"
  },

  {
    question: "He will travel to Europe next summer",
    answers: ["Future continuous", "Simple present", "Past continuous", "Simple future"],
    correctAnswer: "Simple future"
  },

  {
    question: "I am currently reading a book",
    answers: ["Simple present", "Simple past", "Present continuous", "Simple future"],
    correctAnswer: "Present continuous"
  },

  {
    question: "They visited their grandparents last weekend",
    answers: ["Future continuous", "Simple present", "Past continuous", "Simple past"],
    correctAnswer: "Simple past"
  },

  {
    question: "My sister cooks desserts every weekend",
    answers: ["Past continuous", "Simple past", "Simple present", "Simple future"],
    correctAnswer: "Simple present"
  },

    {
      
      question: "Did you go to the beach last summer?",
      // bueno aqui las posibles respuestas, que sean 4 o nos vamos alv 
      answers: ["Simple Past", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Present Continuous"],
      // y aqui la respuesta correcta de la pregunta okaa pero usted ya 
      //ha pegado alguna de ,la snop de :D buenoo estas las dejamos da igual
      correctAnswer: "Simple Past"
    },

    {
      question: "Where did you study English?",
      answers: ["Simple Past", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Present Continuous"],
      correctAnswer: "Simple Past"
    },
    {
      question: "Do you like reading books?",
      answers: ["Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Present Simple"
    },
    {
      question: "Where do you work?",
      answers: ["Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Present Simple"
    },
    {
      question: "Will they visit their relatives next month?",
      answers: ["Simple Future", "Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Simple Future"
    },
    {
      question: "What will you do during the summer vacation?",
      answers: ["Simple Future", "Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Simple Future"
    },
    {
      question: "Are they playing soccer at the moment?",
      answers: ["Present Continuous", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Present Continuous"
    },
    {
      question: "What are you wearing today?",
      answers: ["Present Continuous", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Present Continuous"
    },
    {
      question: "Will you be studying tomorrow evening?",
      answers: ["Future Continuous", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Future Continuous"
    },
    {
      question: "What will you be doing at this time next week?",
      answers: ["Future Continuous", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Future Continuous"
    },
    {
        question: "I play soccer every weekend",
        answers: ["Present Simple", "Simple Past", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Simple"
      },
      {
        question: "She watches TV every evening",
        answers: ["Present Simple", "Simple Past", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Simple"
      },
      {
        question: "They are studying for the exam right now",
        answers: ["Present Continuous", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "He will go to the party tomorrow",
        answers: ["Future Simple", "Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Simple Past"],
        correctAnswer: "Future Simple"
      },
      {
        question: "Did you eat breakfast this morning",
        answers: ["Simple Past", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Present Continuous"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple Past"
      },
      {
        question: "We are going to the movies tonight",
        answers: ["Future Simple", "Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Simple Past"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "She will study abroad next year",
        answers: ["Future Simple", "Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Simple Past"],
        correctAnswer: "Future Simple"
      },
      {
        question: "I lived in London for five years",
        answers: ["Simple Past", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Present Continuous"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple Past"
      },
      {
        question: "He plays the guitar every day",
        answers: ["Present Simple", "Simple Past", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Simple"
      },
      {
        question: "She is cooking dinner right now",
        answers: ["Present Continuous", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Continuous"
      },

      {
        question: "I was an English teacher last year",
        answers: ["Simple past", "Simple future", "past continuous", "present continuous"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple past"
      },

      {
        question: "I will sing at the family karaoke",
        answers: ["Simple future", "Future continuous", "simple past", "simple present"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple future"
      },

      {
        question: "I love my sister, she is my best friend",
        answers: ["simple present", "Simple future", "simple past", "simple present"],
        correctAnswer: "simple present"
      },
    
       {
         question: "I ate pizza last night",
         answers: ["Simple future", "Simple past", "Past continuous", "simple present"],
         correctAnswer: "simple present"
       },
    
      {
        question: 'What is the past simple form of the verb "eat?"',
        answers: ["Eaten", "Ate", "Eating", "Eats"],
        correctAnswer: "Ate"
      },
    
      {
        question: 'What is the present simple form of the verb "do"?',
        answers: ["Done", "Did", "Doing", "Does"],
        correctAnswer: "Does"
      },

      {
        question: 'What is the past simple form of the verb "break"?',
        answers: ["Breaking", "Broke", "Breaks", "Broken"],
        correctAnswer: "Broke"
      },
    
      {
        question: 'What is the future continuous form of the verb "work"?',
        answers: ["Will be working", "Works", "Worked", "Work"],
        correctAnswer: "Will be working"
      },

      {
        question: 'What is the past simple form of the verb "drink"?',
        answers: ["Drinking", "Drinks", "Drinked", "Drank"],
        correctAnswer: "Drank"
      },

      
      {
        question: 'What is the present simple form of the verb "go"?',
        answers: ["Gone", "Going", "Went", "Goes"],
        correctAnswer: "Goes"
      },
    



    
  ];
  
  // Preguntas de dificultad media
  const mediumQuestions = [
    {
      question: "Did you visit your grandparents last weekend?",
      answers: ["Simple Past", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Present Continuous"],
      correctAnswer: "Simple Past"
    },
    {
      question: "What did you watch on TV last night?",
      answers: ["Simple Past", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Present Continuous"],
      correctAnswer: "Simple Past"
    },
    {
      question: "Do they go to the gym frequently?",
      answers: ["Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Present Simple"
    },
    {
      question: "Where do you usually go for a walk?",
      answers: ["Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Present Simple"
    },
    {
      question: "Will you buy a new car next year?",
      answers: ["Simple Future", "Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Simple Future"
    },
    {
      question: "What will you eat for dinner tomorrow?",
      answers: ["Simple Future", "Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Simple Future"
    },
    {
      question: "Are you studying for your final exams?",
      answers: ["Present Continuous", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Present Continuous"
    },
    {
      question: "What are you preparing for dinner tonight?",
      answers: ["Present Continuous", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Present Continuous"
    },
    {
      question: "Will they be traveling during the summer vacation?",
      answers: ["Future Continuous", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Future Continuous"
    },
    {
      question: "What will you be wearing to the party next Saturday?",
      answers: ["Future Continuous", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Future Continuous"
    },
    {
        question: "We went to the beach last summer?",
        answers: ["Simple Past", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Present Continuous"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple Past"
      },
      {
        question: "He is watching a movie at the moment",
        answers: ["Present Continuous", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "They often go hiking on weekends",
        answers: ["Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Simple"
      },
      {
        question: "She usually drinks coffee in the morning",
        answers: ["Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Simple"
      },
      {
        question: "I will be studying for the exam tomorrow",
        answers: ["Future Continuous", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
        correctAnswer: "Future Continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "He is going to the party next Friday",
        answers: ["Future Simple", "Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Simple Past"],
        correctAnswer: "Future Simple"
      },
      {
        question: "They are working on a new project this week",
        answers: ["Present Continuous", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "We are having dinner at a restaurant tonight?",
        answers: ["Present Continuous", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "She will be traveling to Europe next month?",
        answers: ["Future Continuous", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
        correctAnswer: "Future Continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "What are you doing this weekend?",
        answers: ["Present Continuous", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Continuous"
      },

      {
        question: "What will she be doing tomorrow?",
        answers: ["Future continuous", "Simple present", "Past continuous", "Simple future"],
        correctAnswer: "Future continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "When will we be having dinner at a restaurant?",
        answers: ["Simple present", "Simple past", "Present continuous", "Future continuous"],
        correctAnswer: "Future continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "What was he doing when he injured his ankle playing basketball?",
        answers: ["Future continuous", "Simple present", "Past continuous", "Simple future"],
        correctAnswer: "Past continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "Where will they meet later?",
        answers: ["Future continuous", "Simple present", "Future simple", "Simple past"],
        correctAnswer: "Future simple"
      },
      {
        question: "Where will I work?",
        answers: ["Simple present", "Simple past", "Present continuous", "Simple future"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple future"
      },
      {
        question: "What did she do when she went to the store?",
        answers: ["Future continuous", "Simple present", "Past continuous", "Simple past"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple past"
      },
      {
        question: "Will you go to the reservation at the restaurant this weekend? I paid for all the food last night",
        answers: ["Simple future and simple past", "past continuous and simple past", "future continuous and simple past", "simple future and past continuous"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple future and simple past"
      },
      {
        question: "I will be staying at home during these vacations, I really have no money to go to a hotel",
        answers: ["Simple future", "future continuous", "simple present", "past continuous"],
        correctAnswer: "future continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "I was thinking about all the things we have experienced already, and I think we have to get married as soon as possible",
        answers: ["Simple past", "simple present", "past continuous", "present continuous"],
        correctAnswer: "past continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "I'm _______ at the street, she‚Äôs walking, and my mom is swimming at the pool, all of us are doing exercise! The word in the blank must be in the tense of:",
        answers: ["simple past", "simple future", "future continuous", "present continuous"],
        correctAnswer: "present continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "All the people have different ideologies, and we have to be respectful and have our own criticism to live in this new society",
        answers: ["Simple present", "simple future", "past continuous", "present continuous"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple present"
      },
      
      {
        question: "Which sentence uses the present simple tense correctly?",
        answers: ["She was playing tennis yesterday", "They will go to the beach tomorrow", "He runs every day", "I am cooking dinner right now"],
        correctAnswer: "He runs every day"
      },
      {
        question: "Which sentence uses the present simple tense correctly?",
        answers: ["I will travel to London next week", "They were sleeping all night", "He reads a book every night", "She plays the piano every Saturday"],
        correctAnswer: "He reads a book every night"
      },
      {
        question: "Which sentence uses the past continuous tense correctly?",
        answers: ["We will be cooking dinner later", "They ran in the marathon yesterday", "He will write a letter tomorrow", "She was studying all night"],
        correctAnswer: "She was studying all night"
      },
      {
        question: "Which sentence uses the future continuous tense correctly?",
        answers: ["They were playing football all day", "She will be going to the gym tomorrow", "He is sleeping right now", "We have been working for hours"],
        correctAnswer: "She will be going to the gym tomorrow"
      },
      {
        question: "Which sentence uses the present continous tense correctly?",
        answers: ["We were playing chess yesterday", "They will swim in the lake tomorrow", "He is reading a book right now", "She has been cooking for hours"],
        correctAnswer: "He is reading a book right now"
      },
      {
        question: "Which sentence uses the present simple tense correctly?",
        answers: ["We are going to the park yesterday", "They will eat lunch tomorrow", "He eats breakfast every morning", "She is watching"],
        correctAnswer: "He eats breakfast every morning"
      },
      {
        question: "Mom, you were in Canada on vacation? I don't know that, I hope you hace enjoyed it a lot ",
        answers: ["Simple future and simple past", "simple past and Present Perfect", "past continuous and simple future", "simple present and simple past"],
        correctAnswer: "simple past and Present Perfect"
      },
  ];
  

  // Preguntas dif√≠ciles
  const difficultQuestions = [
    {
      question: "Did they finish the project on time?",
      answers: ["Simple Past", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Present Continuous"],
      correctAnswer: "Simple Past"
    },
    {
      question: "What did you have for dinner yesterday?",
      answers: ["Simple Past", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Present Continuous"],
      correctAnswer: "Simple Past"
    },
    {
      question: "Does she speak three languages?",
      answers: ["Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Present Simple"
    },
    {
      question: "Where do they buy their groceries?",
      answers: ["Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Present Simple"
    },
    {
      question: "Will they achieve their goals in the future?",
      answers: ["Simple Future", "Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Simple Future"
    },
    {
      question: "What will you do if you win the lottery?",
      answers: ["Simple Future", "Present Simple", "Present Continuous", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Simple Future"
    },
    {
      question: "Is the tree growing in the garden?",
      answers: ["Present Continuous", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Present Continuous"
    },
    {
      question: "What are they discussing in the meeting?",
      answers: ["Present Continuous", "Present Simple", "Future Simple", "Simple Past"],
      correctAnswer: "Present Continuous"
    },
    {
        question: "He had already finished the book",
        answers: ["Past Perfect", "Past Simple", "Present Perfect", "Past Continuous"],
        correctAnswer: "Past Perfect"
      },
      {
        question: "She has been studying for six hours",
        answers: ["Present Perfect Continuous", "Present Perfect", "Past Perfect", "Past Simple"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Perfect Continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "They will have arrived by tomorrow",
        answers: ["Future Perfect", "Future Simple", "Present Perfect", "Present Simple"],
        correctAnswer: "Future Perfect"
      },
      {
        question: "He had been working all day",
        answers: ["Past Perfect Continuous", "Past Perfect", "Present Perfect", "Past Simple"],
        correctAnswer: "Past Perfect Continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "She will have been studying for five years by next month",
        answers: ["Future Perfect Continuous", "Future Perfect", "Present Perfect", "Present Simple"],
        correctAnswer: "Future Perfect Continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "He has lived in this city since 2010",
        answers: ["Present Perfect", "Present Simple", "Past Perfect", "Past Simple"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Perfect"
      },
      {
        question: "They will have finished the project by the end of the week",
        answers: ["Future Perfect", "Future Simple", "Present Perfect", "Present Simple"],
        correctAnswer: "Future Perfect"
      },
      {
        question: "She had been studying English before she moved to the United States",
        answers: ["Past Perfect Continuous", "Past Perfect", "Present Perfect", "Past Simple"],
        correctAnswer: "Past Perfect Continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "We will have been working on this project for a year by December",
        answers: ["Future Perfect Continuous", "Future Perfect", "Present Perfect", "Present Simple"],
        correctAnswer: "Future Perfect Continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "He has been running marathons since he was a teenager",
        answers: ["Present Perfect Continuous", "Present Perfect", "Past Perfect", "Past Simple"],
        correctAnswer: "Present Perfect Continuous"
      },

      {
        question: "She will travel to Europe next summer",
        answers: ["Future continuous", "Simple present", "Past continuous", "Simple future"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple future"
      },
      {
        question: "Every summer, they go on a road trip across the country, exploring new places and meeting interesting people",
        answers: ["Simple present", "Simple past", "Present continuous", "Simple future"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple present"
      },
      {
        question: "While he was studying abroad, she was working on her master's degree, conducting research in the field of astrophysics",
        answers: ["Future continuous", "Simple present", "Past continuous", "Simple future"],
        correctAnswer: "Past continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "In two years, we will complete the construction of our new house",
        answers: ["Future continuous", "Simple present", "Past continuous", "Simple future"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple future"
      },
      {
        question: "They are currently training for the marathon, running long distances, and following a strict diet and exercise regimen",
        answers: ["Simple present", "Simple past", "Present continuous", "Simple future"],
        correctAnswer: "Present continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "Last night, he wrote a heartfelt letter expressing his gratitude to his mentors, acknowledging their guidance and support throughout his career",
        answers: ["Future continuous", "Simple present", "Past continuous", "Simple past"],
        correctAnswer: ""
      },
      {
        question: "Jessica is ____ her homework right now, I'm helping her because she doesn't understand the topic of this subject. I hope she understands English before the end of the semester. The word in the blank must be in the tense:",
        answers: ["Future continuous", "Simple future", "simple past", "present continuous"],
        correctAnswer: "present continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "My mom was a mechanic last week, our family was stranded in the middle of the road, it was chaotic. As my mom started the car, we had to push from behind. All the sentences belong to the verb tense:",
        answers: ["Simple past", "Simple future", "past continuous", "Simple present"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple past"
      },
      {
        question: "Sometimes my friends and I like to go to the mountain to camp. We___ stars yesterday, and they looked beautiful, but my friends were shocked looking at the sky. The word in the blank must be in the tense of:",
        answers: ["past continuous", "simple present", "simple future", "Simple past"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple past"
      },
      {
        question: "I have to take the university admission test this year. I really want to study at Universidad de Costa Rica, I believe in my abilities so I'm sure I ___ pass the exam. The word in the blank must be in the tense of:",
        answers: ["Future continuous", "simple present", "past continuous", "simple future"],
        correctAnswer: "simple future"
      },
      {
        question: "Which tense is used to express an action that will happen in the future?",
        answers: ["Simple future", "Simple past", "Past continuous", "Simple future"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple future"
      },
      {
        question: "Which tense is used to describe an action that has already happened and finished in the past?",
        answers: ["Simple past", "Simple future", "Past continuous", "Present continous"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple past"
      },
      {
        question: "Which tense is used to express an action that was happening in the past and got interrupted by another action?",
        answers: ["Simple future", "Past continuous", "Simple past", "Simple present"],
        correctAnswer: "Past continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "Which tense is used to describe an action that will be in progress in the future?",
        answers: ["Future continuous", "Present continuous", "Simple present", "Simple past"],
        correctAnswer: "Future continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "Which tense is used to express an action that is happening at this moment?",
        answers: ["Future continuous", "Present continuous", "Simple present", "Simple past"],
        correctAnswer: "Present continuous"
      },
      {
        question: "Which tense is used to talk about a habitual or general action?",
        answers: ["Simple present", "Future continuous", "Present continuous", "Simple past"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple present"
      },
      {
        question: "I still remember when I was a child, I could run a lot, do all the things I wanted. The life was much easier than now.",
        answers: ["Simple present and simple past", "Simple past and simple future", "Past continuous and simple future", "Simple past and future continuous"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple present and simple past"
      },
                                                                    
    ];
  